<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Just Some Digital Humanities Research Projects</title>
    <link>https://sigita-sevceva.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Just Some Digital Humanities Research Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:36:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sigita-sevceva.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Recently Found Out What Captology Means</title>
      <link>https://sigita-sevceva.github.io/posts/captology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:36:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sigita-sevceva.github.io/posts/captology/</guid>
      <description>And Did A Small Research on Surveillance Capitalism Background This research was part of my Human Rights, Ethics and Technology study course at TalTech. In this paper, I looked at the notion and examples of captology with the aim to argue whether such infrastructure of surveillance economy is not in tension with freedom in a general sense as well as human rights and individual autonomy, which serve as some of the key foundations of democratic life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Made A Machine Learning Model For Analysing Movie Reviews So You Don&#39;t Have To</title>
      <link>https://sigita-sevceva.github.io/posts/sentiment-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 12:46:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sigita-sevceva.github.io/posts/sentiment-analysis/</guid>
      <description>The Goal Have you ever based your decision on whether to watch a movie or not on other people&amp;rsquo;s reviews and feedback? I have. So naturally, I wanted to create a program that would help me decide. Thus, I created a machine learning model in Python for scalar/degree sentiment analysis to train labeling positive versus negative film reviews, by analysing their features and adjectives, in case anyone wants to use it on a corpus of any kind of film reviews (it might not be so accurate on other types of corpora, as I&amp;rsquo;ve only trained it on films, but you might try!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Tried Analysing Trump&#39;s Speeches</title>
      <link>https://sigita-sevceva.github.io/posts/natural-language-processing-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sigita-sevceva.github.io/posts/natural-language-processing-5/</guid>
      <description>And this is how it turned out It all started when I saw a corpus of transcribed pre-election rally speeches by Donald Trump. It sparked an interest in me to run a short overall analysis of it not going into many details or listening to each one of them (that would be tough, to say the least). For anyone interested, the corpus can be found on Kaggle
For the analysis, I mainly used Natural Language Processing Toolkit libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
